# TAKRIM RAHMAN ALBI

## **Data Scientist | Software Engineer**

- takrim.rahman.albi@g.bracu.ac.bd
- **J** +880-1625212429
- Mirpur-12, Dhaka- 1216, Bangladesh Alvi-Rahman
- takrim-rahman-albi.github.io/



# **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer

#### Go Zayaan

March 2020 - Ongoing

Dhaka, Bangladesh

## Mentor | Data Scientist

#### **Omdena**

April 2021 - Ongoing

Remote, United States

# Data Scientist and Python Developer

#### **Codeware Limited**

**a** August 2020 - March2020

Dhaka, Bangladesh

# **CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Member at youth Moch Parliament (2016)
- Design For Change (BRAC University RS Activity)

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Data Science and AI Projects:**

## **Paraphrase Tool Using Neural Machine Translation**

Alvi-Rahman/Paraphrase-Tool-NMT

#### **Omdena- Road Safety in Bangladesh**

OmdenaAl/omdena-bangladesh-roadsafety

#### Deep Learning Projects (DeepLearning.ai)

Alvi-Rahman/Deep-Learning-Coursera—deeplearning.ai

#### **GAN Projects**

Alvi-Rahman/GAN-Specialization

## **Natural Language Processing (Coursera)**

Alvi-Rahman/Natural-Language-Processing-Specialization

## **Computer Vision Projects**

Alvi-Rahman/Computer-Vision-with-OpenCV-and-Python

# **PROFILE**

Having a curious mind and always willing to learn, I am an enthusiastic Data Scientist who is ready to take challenges and provide something state of the art using my skills and expertise not only to the Science community but also to the business domain.

# **EDUCATION**

BSc. in Computer Science and Engineering

#### **BRAC UNIVERSITY**

**2016 - 2020** 

Dhaka, Bangladesh

CGPA - 3.54 out of 4

# **SKILLS**

## **Programming**

- Strong Knowledge In Data Structure and Algorithms
- Experience in Programming Contest
- Problem Solving and Critical Thinking

#### **Data Science**

#### Experienced in:

- ML and DL algorithms from scratch
- Data Pre-processing, creating Data and Model Pipelines, EDA, Graph Analytics
- DNNs, Computer Vision, Sequence, Attention and Transformers models, GANs
- Hyper Parameter Tuning and Optimization
- Specialized in Deep Learning Frameworks such as Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch, Trax
- Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, NetworkX, OpenCV, Pillow, SpaCy, NLTK, Nilearn, Hadoop and Spark
- Deploying AI models

#### **Development**

- Django, Flask, React, Node, Bootstrap
- RESTful APIs, Serializers, DRF
- All social app authentication/authorization, GraphAPI, social permissions and apps
- Mysql, MongoDB, Postgres, Firebase
- · Docker, Git, Nginx, Apache, AWS

#### **Stanford Machine Learning (Coursera)**

Alvi-Rahman/Coursera-Machine-Learning-Andrew-Ng

#### **Tensorflow in Practice (Coursera)**

Alvi-Rahman/Tensorflow\_in\_practice\_Coursera

## **Self Driving Car Projects**

Alvi-Rahman/Self-Driving-Car-Specialization

#### Al for Medicine Projects

Alvi-Rahman/Al-for-Medicine-Coursera

#### **Natural Language Processing Projects**

Alvi-Rahman/NLP—Natural-Language-Processing-with-Python

#### Python Data Science (Scikit-Learn and ML)

Alvi-Rahman/Python\_Data\_Science\_and\_Machine\_Learning

# **Development Projects:**

#### Go Zayaan Backend

gozayaan.com

#### All Social Media Under One Platform

idesk360.com

# **Tech Review Site**

www.gsmriders.com

#### Project Likhoni (Android Based Social Media)

Alvi-Rahman/Project Likhoni Android

#### **Accounting Software (JAVA)**

Alvi-Rahman/Accounting\_Software\_JAVA

## Some Other Mentionable Projects:

# CAT-Chain: A Blockchain Based Categorical Information Transaction And Depository Framework

Alvi-Rahman/CAT-Chain

#### Some Solutions for Online Judge Problems

Alvi-Rahman/Programming\_Contest\_Problem\_Solve

# **PUBLICATIONS**

 Honorable Mention Award ACM CSCW 2020: Learning from Tweets: Opportunities and Challenges to Inform Policy Making During Dengue Epidemic. Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact. 4, CSCW1, Article 065 (May 2020) DOI:https://doi.org/10.1145/3392875

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**



1st Runners UP (MUJIB BORSHO IT CARNIVAL 2020- DIU)

View Certificate

# **CERTIFICATIONS**



**Deep Learning Specialization** 

View Certificate



Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) Specialization

View Certificate



**BIG DATA Specialization** 

View Certificate



**Self-Driving Car Specialization** 

View Certificate



**TensorFlow Developer** 

View Certificate



Al for Medicine Specialization

View Certificate



**Stanford Machine Learning Coursera** 

View Certificate



Natural Language Processing Specialization

View Certificate



Al For Everyone

View Certificate



AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud-Native

View Certificate



**BIRDS Workshop** 

View Certificate

# REFERENCES

## Prof. Sriram Chellappan, Ph.D

@ University of South Florida

csee.usf.edu/~sriramc/

## Prof. A. B. M. Alim Al Islam, PhD

- @ Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology
- ✓ alim\_razi@cse.buet.ac.bd
- sites.google.com/site/abmalimalislam/